<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bug, Duck, Goose (Posts about Blog Related)</title><link>https://noahericksonpdx.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://noahericksonpdx.com/categories/cat_blog-related.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:noahterickson@gmail.com"&gt;Noah Erickson&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 15:36:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Give A Blog A Good Name</title><link>https://noahericksonpdx.com/blog/give-a-blog-a-good-name/</link><dc:creator>Noah Erickson</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I stated in my "Hello World" post this blog is mainly intended to be my personal book journal. Despite the blogs purpose, I didn't want to limit it's scope unecessarily and thought
I should give it a broader name than just "Book Blog" which is what I had started calling it. During a brief period of cleverness (while doing something completely unrelated) I came
up with the name "Bug, Duck, Goose", a play on the children's game "Duck, Duck, Goose."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now please sit tight and allow me to explain the cleverness behind the name by talking first about bugs. My dayjob consists
of developing a a little bit  of software to aid the development of even more firmware. For whatever reason, bugs are pretty much inevitable in any of the projects that I have been
exposed to in my education and career. It's a natural part of software development and the reason that debugging and testing practices are necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ducks are an invaluable way to debug issues in code. The idea here, which is not my own (the origins of rubber duck debugging could be found by a quick Google search), is that if a person who is developing a piece
of software runs into a bug they may figure out how to fix the bug if they can explain the problem to a rubber duck. The rubber duck here isn't important, it could be any animal
or coworker for that matter. This method is so effective that I have a rubber duck (with sunglasses) on my desk at work that sits even closer to me than my nearest coworker. I also try
my best to provide rubber ducks to anyone in need of one at my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geese are a common sighting at my companies' campus which has a small pond and quite a bit of grass. Every spring we get large flocks of both Canadian and Cackling geese. Putting goose
in the blogs' name seemed natural since I often swivel around in my chair while debugging an issue and watch the geese graze their way across our fields of grass. As a semi-related
anecdote my team at work has spotted a tracked goose twice in the past couple of years and submitted the collared goose's name to the USGS. The gooses' name will be omitted from this blog
for privacy reasons but he has become somewhat of a mascot to our team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this posting gives a bit more insight into the blogs name which may seem a bit silly at first. I also hope you find it clever and don't think I'm just a quack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, keeping with the unecessarily limited book scope of this blog, the name of this posting is inspired by Part 4, Chapter 7 of How to Win Friends &amp;amp; Influence People by Dale Carnegie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Blog Related</category><guid>https://noahericksonpdx.com/blog/give-a-blog-a-good-name/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 02:25:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://noahericksonpdx.com/blog/hello-world/</link><dc:creator>Noah Erickson</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This blog will mainly serve as my personal journal for books I've read and is intended to be nothing more than a collection of my thoughts. Despite being a blog for my own personal use I realize this is public and accessible by anyone who stumbles upon it so I will provide a quick introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm an electrical engineer living in Portland focused on embedded firmware development. I spend most of my workday behind a keyboard developing software yet I do not have a knack for writing. I find a lot of enjoyment in my work and my favorite work days are the ones where I sit at my desk developing Python test scripts, bringing up a new micro-controller or optimizing some older code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My free time is spent with my wife hanging out around the house. Various house projects and gardening keep us busy enough but we also spend our fair share watching movies together, playing video games and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I have found a handful of books on our bookshelf with cracked spines but I do not recall their contents. This discovery prompted me to start this blog. I enjoy reading science fiction (Warhammer 40K space operas) but actively try to read more classic books as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm starting this blog off with a typical hello world post. My intention is to write a post per chapter I complete but I am unsure if I have the diligence to keep up with this schedule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Blog Related</category><guid>https://noahericksonpdx.com/blog/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:10:11 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>